Guide to the Joseph A. Goney Papers, 1914-1967 AIS.2010.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Joseph A. Goney Papers
1914-1967
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Goney, Joseph A.
AIS.2010.11
1.68 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Joseph A. Goney served as an officer in several labor organizations, including the Steel Workers Organizing Committee, United Steelworkers of America, Association of Catholic Trade Unionists, the Allegheny County CIO Political Action Committee and Steel City Industrial Union Council. This collection contains correspondence and newspaper clippings documenting Pittsburgh area labor history, particularly the 1937 strike by SWOC Local 1601 at Heppenstall Steel Company. Photographs of USWA events are also included.
Related Material
Francis C. Shane Papers, 1942-1969, AIS.1996.03, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Charles Owen Rice Papers, 1935-1998, AIS.1976.11, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Allegheny County Committee on Fair Employment Practice Records, 1945-1946, 1950, AIS.1969.11, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Previous Citation
Joseph A. Goney Papers, 1914-1967, AIS.2010.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Biography
Joseph A. Goney began his labor union career as financial secretary of Amalgamated Association of Iron, Steel and Tin Workers Lodge 1601 at Heppenstall Steel Company in 1937. He was president and national council representative for the Pittsburgh chapter of the Association of Catholic Trade Unionists, chairman of the Allegheny County CIO Political Action Committee and secretary of the Steel City Industrial Union Council. After serving as the United Steelworkers of America District 17 director and Assistant Director of the Safety and Health Department, Goney retired to become a member of the Pittsburgh Housing Authority board.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains correspondence and newspaper clippings documenting the 1937 strike by SWOC Local 1601 at Heppenstall Steel Company in the Lawrenceville neighborhood of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, and Joseph A. Goney's 1949 re-election as director of United Steelworkers of America District 17. Photographs of Goney, Father Charles Owen Rice, and Pittsburgh Mayor David Lawrence at several labor related functions, as well as the Heppenstall strike are also present. Also included are scrapbooks containing newspaper articles regarding labor related stories in the Pittsburgh area.
Personal papers; Labor; Photographs; Clippings (Information artifacts); Labor leaders -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Iron and steel workers -- Labor unions -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; United Steelworkers of America. District 17; Goney, Joseph A.; Amalgamated Association of Iron, Steel and Tin Workers of North America. Lodge 1601 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Association of Catholic Trade Unionists. Pittsburgh Chapter; Heppenstall Steel Company
- Ritual of the Amalgamated Association of Iron, Steel and Tin Workers of North America, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Heppenstall Steel Company and Steel Workers Organizing Committee Lodge 1601, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
- Association of Catholic Trade Unionists, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1935, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- District 17 Election, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Labor Management Council of Pittsburgh, 1947, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Inter-Office Telephone Directory, United Steelworkers of America, June 30, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publications on Presidency and Labor Unions, 1944, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence and Newspaper Clippings, 1943-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Zigmont Pazskowski and Joseph Robinson, Local 1276 Trial, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CIO 7th Constitutional Convention Badge and First District Convention SWOC Badge Signed by Philip Murray, 1940, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clipping, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Steel City Industrial Union Council, 1941, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1937-1950s (Box 2)
- Photograph, Penn Industrial Union Council Convention, USWA District 17 Delegates, 1943 (Box 3, Item 1)
- Photograph, Joseph Goney (Box 3, Item 2)
- Photograph, District 17 Staff, 1944 (Box 3, Item 3)
- Photograph, SWOC Second Convention, Lawrenceville/North Side District, 1941 (Box 3, Item 4-6)
- Poster, "To the Public and the Employees in the Steel Industry", March 20, 1937 (Box 3, Item 7)
- Scrapbook of Pittsburgh Labor Articles, 1942-1952 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- USWA Local 3657 Contract Negotiations, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)